Good afternoon my name is Tom Brintzenhofe I'm here out of Reading, Pennsylvania to show you how to change car brakes.
I've already got the wheel off, I got this thing up and supported to make time a little bit easier.
What you want to do is look at your assembly here your brake caliper, the only typically just two bolts holding it in.
I've already located and loosened the bolts for you.
You are going to take them out or take on of them out.
Rotate this upwards it's going to expose your entry front brake pads, real simple just pull them right out.
And again make sure you hold on to this.
The last thing you want to do is drop that down on your fingers.
Grab one of your brand new brake pads and slide it in there.
Ok you want to take your inside brake pad stick it in the holder there, get in the back one.
Take your old brake pad either way it doesn't matter that way or that way.
Grab your brake tool you can find it in any local parts store.
They are under ten dollars.
You want to slide that in here and push that in there to get both pistons you can actually see it going back in.
You want to make sure both of them are all the way in, get them turned in there like that.
Slide your caliber back over your new brake pads get your bolts back in tighten everything back up just remember pump your brake pedal up a few times before you go pulling out because your piston won't be exposed on your brake pads right away.
That's all you need to do.
Tighten her up and you are good to go.